howardwilson

contact

howard@watsonbox.net

github.com/watsonbox watsonbox.github.com

languages

english mother tongue fluent french

programming

♥ Ruby / Rails Ember.js, Swift, Python CSS3 & HTML5 AWS/EC2, Git, RSpec

profile

Highly motivated I.T. professional, capable of integrating quickly into existing teams, applying relevant skills and technologies where appropriate. Experienced in achieving the highest standards of development, with careful appreciation of project timescales and resource. Good communication skills; confident and articulate.

education

2001–2004 **Computer Science** BSc Hons

The University of Warwick, England

Paris, France

First Class - 80% Average.

Freelance - Various Projects

Third Year Project - 89% awarded 'Project of the Year 2004'.

experience

2014-Now

	Ember.js, Swift/iOS, Docker/Dokku
2012–2014	Fanzy Paris, France Technical Team Lead / CTO
	Ruby on Rails 3.2, Goliath, Sinatra, AWS/EC2/RDS, Elasticsearch, MongoDB, Social APIs, Scrum, TDD
2011-2012	eYeka Paris, France
	Senior Developer / Technical Team Lead Ruby on Rails, Gigya Social Login/Sharing
2010-2011	Smartdate Paris, France
	Senior Developer - Contract Ruby on Rails 2.3, AWS/EC2, NoSQL stores, memcached, collaborative matching, Facebook Graph API, Scrum, TDD
2009-2010	Halogen Solutions Limited Paris, France
	Managing Director - Self Employed Ruby on Rails 2.2, MySQL, Linux systems administration
2008-2009	Smart Business Communications Paris, France
	EMEA e-Learning Project Manager - Contract PHP, MySQL, Ruby on Rails 2.1, Linux systems administration
2006-2008	RM Education Plc Didcot, Oxfordshire, UK
	Technical Team Lead - Contract C#, ASP.NET, COM+, Transact-SQL
2006	Sygneca Ltd Cliddesden, Hampshire, UK Web Application Developer - Contract Scala
2004-2006	Dorset Software Services <pre>.NET/C# Consultant Analyst Programmer</pre> Poole, Dorset, UK